-=圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hdscg.com/=-
仅供翻译交流使用, 禁止用于商业用途
协调: 影子   校对: 颐译辜形
翻译: 灵峰 肉肉君 jackhawktaobao 喵喵 沉默的土豆
你可曾看着某人而感到好奇
Do you ever look at someone and wonder.
他的脑袋里在想什么呢?
What is going on inside their head?
嗯 这我知道
Well, I know.
额 我很了解莱莉的头脑
Well, I know Riley's head.
这就是她
And there she was.
哈罗
Hello.
- 莱莉  - 哇 看
- Riley.  - Whoa. Look at you.
你可不就是小乐乐嘛
Aren't you a little bundle of joy.
哇
Whoa.
真不可思议 就莱莉和我两个人
It was amazing. Just Riley and me
永远在一起
forever.
或者
Or for
仅仅33秒
33 seconds.
我是忧忧
I'm Sadness.
你好 我是乐乐 那
Oh, hello. I'm Joy. So.
我可以 你能不能让...
Can I just, if you could...
额 让我按一下 谢谢
I don't know, let me fix that. Thanks.
而这只是开始
And that was just the beginning.
大脑总部从此只会越来越挤
Headquarters only got more crowded from there.
很好 看来你学会了
Very nice. Okay. Looks like you got this.
很不错 噢 危险! 危险!
Very good. Oh. Sharp! Sharp!
别 当心!
No, Look out!
这就是怕怕 在保证莱莉安全方面他很在行
That's Fear. He's really good at keeping Riley safe.
小心 小心
Easy. Easy.
退后! 喔 幸好没事
Fall back! Oh, we're good.
完事
We're good.
- 呜 干得好  - 多谢 非常感谢
- Woo. Good job.  - Thank you. Thank you very much.
接着 小跑起来
And. We're back.
哇
Whoa.
吃饭啦 张嘴
Here we go, alright. Open.
- 嗯 没见过  - 觉得安全吗?
- Hm. This looks new.  - Think it's safe?
- 这到底是什么?  - 啊...
- What is it?  - Ah...
好了 警惕点 这里有股危险的气息 亲们
Okay, caution. There is a dangerous smell, people.
等等 那是什么?
Hold on. What is that?
这是厌厌
This is Disgust.
她让莱莉免受身体和精神上的毒害
She basically keeps Riley from being poisoned, physically and socially.
颜色不够亮
That is not brightly colored.
形状也不像是恐龙 慢点儿
Or shaped like a dinosaur. Hold on guys.
西兰花! 讨厌!
It's broccoli! Blah!
不要吃!
Yucky!
我刚救了大家的性命
Well. I just saved our lives.
不客气啦
Yeah. You're welcome.
莱莉 如果你不好好吃饭 可不会有甜点给你吃
Riley, if you don't eat your dinner, you're not going to get any dessert.
等等 他是说我们没有甜点吃了?
Wait. Did he just say we couldn't have dessert?
那是怒怒 他...
That's Anger. He...
非常在意事情公平与否
cares very deeply about things being fair.
那么 你想这么和我玩吗 老头儿
So, that's how you want to play it, old man.
不给甜点? 可以啊 让你先尝尝我的厉害
No dessert? Oh, sure. We'll eat our dinner.
我再吃饭!
Right after you eat this!
啊!
Arh!
莱莉 莱莉 飞机来咯
Riley, Riley. Here comes an airplane.
噢 飞机诶 有飞机了 亲们
Oh, airplane. We got an airplane, everybody.
- 噢  - 噢
- Oh.  - Oh.
你见过忧忧了
And you've met Sadness.
她 额 她...
She. Well, she...
我实在不知道她有什么用
I'm not actually sure what she does.
我也找过了 没有她可去的地方 所以
And I've checked, there's no place for her to go. So.
只要她没事 我们就好 大家都好
She's good. We're good. It's all great.
总之 这些是莱莉的记忆
Anyway. These are Riley's memories.
它们大多是乐乐的 这可不是在炫耀
And they are mostly happy if you noticed, not to brag.
不过最重要的记忆在这里
But the really important ones are over here.
我不想说得太过学术 不过这些叫做
I don't want to get too technical but these are called
核心记忆
core memories.
每一颗都来自莱莉生命中极为重要的时刻
Each one came from a super important time in Riley's life.
比如她第一次得分 太美妙了
Like when she first scored a goal. It was so amazing.
嘿嘿! 看到了吗
Hey hey! Would you look at that.
- 干得漂亮  - 干得好
- Very nice.  - Nice job.
- 呜呼!  - 耶!
- Woo-hoo!  - Yeah!
每个核心记忆都会塑造莱莉某一方面的个性
And each core memory powers a different aspect of Riley's personality.
比如 冰球岛
Like. Hockey Island.
我最爱嬉戏岛
Goofball Island is my personal favorite.
快过来 小猴子!
Come back here, you little monkey!
耶 嬉戏最赞了
Yup. Goofball is the best.
友情岛也很好啦
Friendship Island is pretty good too.
噢 我爱诚实岛
Oh. I love Honesty Island.
我说的可是真话
And that's the truth.
当然啦 亲情岛很不可思议
And of course, Family Island is amazing.
这些个性之岛是莱莉区别于他人的关键所在
The point is. The islands of personality are what make Riley, Riley.
当心 蓝鲨
Look out, Blue face.
岩浆! 呼!
Lava! Hoo!
你最爱玩的伙伴是谁? 冰棒 冰棒
Who's your friend who likes to play? Bing Bong. Bing Bong.
滑得很好呀
Hey, very nice.
- 啊  - 大脑急冻!
- Agh.  - Brain freeze!
- 啊!  - 啊!
- Agh!  - Ahh!
噢
Aw.
- 耶!  - 耶!
- Yeah!  - Yeh!
- 晚安 孩子  - 晚安 爸爸
- Good night, kiddo.  - Good night, Dad.
然后...
And...
该撤了
We're out.
就该这样 唔! 又是完美的一天
That's what I'm talking about. Woo! Another perfect day.
大家干得漂亮
Nice job everybody.
把这些记忆转成长期的
Let's get those memories down to long term.
很好 我们今天没有死
Alright. We did not die today.
这是完全的胜利
I call that an unqualified success.
介绍完了 我们爱这个女孩
And, that's it. We love our girl.
她有许多好朋友 住在一所大房子里
She's got great friends and a great house.
一切都很好
Things couldn't be better.
毕竟 莱莉11岁了
After all. Riley is 11 now.
还能发生什么呢?
What could happen?
已售
- 什么?  - 啊!
- What?  - Aw!
- 哼!  - 啊!
- Huh!  - Aw!
好吧 这不是我想的那样
Okay. Not what I had in mind.
啊!
Aw!
头脑特工队
快看 金门大桥 好棒
Hey, look. The Golden Gate Bridge, isn't that great?
有点遗憾 它不像我们想的那样 用纯金打造的 不过...
It's not made up of solid gold like we thought, which is kind of disappointment. But still...
我很高兴你告诉我地震是虚构的 乐乐
I sure am glad you told me earthquakes are a myth, Joy.
- 否则现在我会很惊恐  - 额... 算是吧
- Otherwise I'd be terrified right now.  - Uh... Yeah.
找到我的同类啦
These are my kind of people.
好了 再过几个街区
Alright, just a few more blocks.
- 就到新家了  - 加速 老爸
- We're almost to our new house.  - Step on it, Daddy.
何不住在这辆臭不可闻的车里 都已经呆了这么久了
Why don't we just live in the smelly car. We've already been in it forever.
这... 其实很幸运
Which... actually was really lucky.
让我们有足够的时间想象新家的样子
Because that gave us plenty of time to think about what our new house is going to look like.
天啊 再来看看排名前五的白日梦
What? Let's review the top 5 daydreams.
- 看起来很安全  - 不错
- Woo, that looks safe.  - That looks nice.
这样子的很适合莱莉啊 哦! 不不不... 这个才好
Oh. This will be great for Riley. Oh! No, no, no... this one.
再说一次 乐乐 她不能住在曲奇屋里
Joy for the last time. She cannot live in a cookie.
就这个啦 边上有龙
That's the one. It comes with a dragon.
很近了吗? 我感觉到了
Are we getting close? I can feel it.
到了 这就是我们的新家
Here it is. Here's our new house.
然后...
And...
或许 会是金玉其内呢
Maybe, it's nice on the inside.
- 我们要住这里?  - 必须吗?
- We're supposed to live here?  - Do we have to?
我告诉你们 这里闻起来有腐尸的味道
I'm telling you, it smells that something died in here.
- 搬家能死吗?  - 亲们 别那么激动
- Can you die from moving?  - Guys, you are overreacting.
- 没人会死  - 一只死老鼠!
- Nobody is dying.  - A dead mouse!
- 好极了  - 我要吐了
- Great.  - I'm gonna be sick.
这可是死亡之屋 该怎么办?
It's a house of the dead. What're we gonna do?
- 我们会得狂犬病的  - 从我身上下来!
- We're gonna get rabies.  - Get off from me!
嘿嘿嘿 开车途中
Hey, hey, hey. All through the drive,
老爸说我们的新房间很酷
dad talked about how cool our new room is.
- 去看看  - 一定很棒
- Let's go check it out.  - It's gonna be great.
啊 啊 啊 啊!
Yes, yes, yes, yes!
- 不 不 不...  - 我开始嫉妒那只死老鼠了
- No, no, no...  - I'm starting to envy the dead mouse.
把橡皮球拿出来 我们被单独监禁了
Get out the rubber ball. We're in solitary confinement.
莱莉不能住这里
Riley can't live here.
- 她说的对  - 太差了
- She's right.  - It's the worst.
- 相当差  - 绝对是最差的
- Really bad.  - It's absolutely the worst.
- 这房子太烂了  - 是我一生中见过的
- This house stinks.  - It's the worst place
- 最烂的地方  - 说的对
- I've been in my entire life.  - Oh, yeah.
嘿 我们还有蝴蝶窗帘呢
Hey, it's nothing our butterfly curtains couldn't fix.
书上说 空房间是一个机会
I read somewhere that an empty room is an opportunity.
你从哪里读来的?
Where did you read that?
这不重要 我读到过 它也说的很对
It doesn't matter. I read it and it's great.
床放那里 梳妆桌放这里
We'll put the bed there. And the desk over there.
灯放这里
The hockey lamp goes there.
- 椅子放那里  - 或者放收藏的奖杯
- Put the chair there.  - Or the trophy collections.
- 那里...  - 星星!
- There...  - Stars!
- 我喜欢  - 就该这样子
- I like that.  - Now, we're talking.
去搬运车里搬家具吧
Let's go get our stuff from the moving van.
好吧 拜拜 有个不好的消息
Alright. Goodbye. Well, guess what?
搬运车要周四才能过来
The moving van won't be here until Thursday.
你开玩笑吧
You're kidding.
搬运车走丢了? 史上最烂的一天
Our van is lost? It's the worst day ever.
- 你昨天还说搬运车会到的  - 我是这么说的
- You said it would be here yesterday.  - And I know that's what I said.
- 他们是这么说的  - 爸爸妈妈太焦虑了
- That's what they told me.  - Mom and Dad are stressed out.
- 他们太焦虑了  - 吵起来了
- They are stressed out.  - Arguing.
我们怎么办?
What're we going to do?
我有个好主意
I've got a great idea.
你是不是连合同都没有读?
Did you even read the contract?
安德森开始进攻 快速逼近
Anderson makes her move. She's closing in.
嘿 不行 你过不去的
Hey. Oh no, you're not.
- 她带球过人  - 小心背后
- She's running for the shot.  - Coming behind you, watch out.
她得分了! 耶!
And she scores! Yeah!
- 呜呼  - 呦吼
- Woo-hoo.  - Yo-ho.
快来 奶奶
Come on. Grandma.
哈 奶奶?
Ha. Grandma?
喔 她扎头发了 要开战了
Oh-oh, she put her hair up. We're in for it.
嘿 放我下去
Heyyy. Put me down.
- 呵呵呵  - 哈哈
- Eh-heh-heh.  - Haha.
不好意思 等等
Sorry, hold on.
- 你好  - 等等 什么
- Hello.  - Wait. What.
你开玩笑吧
You're kidding.
好吧 先帮我挡挡 马上到
Alright. Stall for me, I'll be right there.
投资方应该周四才到 而不是今天
The investors are supposed to show up on Thursday, not today.
- 我必须走了  - 没事 我们理解
- I got to go.  - It's okay, we get it.
你最好了 谢谢亲爱的 再见 甜心
You're the best. Thanks hon. See you, sweetie.
老爸就这么走了
Dad just left us.
噢 他不再爱我们了 好悲伤
Oh, he doesn't love us anymore. That's sad.
该我了 对吧?
I should drive, right?
乐乐 你干什么?
Joy. What are you doing?
你等等 给我一秒钟
Just you. Give me 1 second.
我刚刚意识到 莱莉还没吃午饭呢 记得吗?
You know what I've realised? Riley hasn't had lunch. Remember?
嘿 来的路上我看到比萨店了 我们去尝尝?
Hey, I saw a pizza place down the street. Maybe we can try that.
- 比萨听起来很好吃  - 比萨
- Pizza sounds delicious.  - Pizza.
- 耶 比萨  - 比萨 好主意 去吃吧
- Yeah, pizza.  - Pizza. Great idea. Let's get it.
- 这是什么鬼?  - 谁会在比萨上放西兰花?
- What the heck is that?  - Who puts broccoli on pizza?
我受够了
That's it. I'm done.
祝贺旧金山成功毁了比萨
Congratulations, San Francisco. You've ruined pizza.
先是夏威夷人 然后是你
First the Hawaiians. And now you.
这算哪门子比萨店? 只提供一种比萨
What kind of a pizza place only serves 1 kind of pizza?
一定是旧金山特有的吧
Must be a San Francisco thing.
不过 这也没有内布拉斯加那家店的汤那么糟
Still, it's not as bad as the soup at that diner in Nebraska.
是的 汤匙都能在汤里立着
Oh, yeah. The spoon stood up in the soup by itself.
太难吃了
That was disgusting.
太好了 亲情岛在工作
We're good. Family's running.
自驾游很有趣 你最喜欢哪一出?
The drive out was pretty fun. What was your favorite part?
朝窗外吐口水
Spitting out of the car window.
- 绝不是老爸唱歌的时候  - 系安全带
- Definitely not when Dad was singing.  - Wearing the seat belt.
哦 在恐龙旁的时候怎么样?
Oh. What about the time with the dinosaur?
- 这个不错  - 确实很棒
- Oh, that's the one.  - That was great.
茄子
Say cheese.
- 爸 爸 爸  - 亲爱的
- Dad. Dad. Dad.  - Honey.
爸 你的车 看你背后
Dad, look at the car. Just look behind you.
不... 不... 不...
No... no... no...
别! 啊
No! Ah.
很不错 乐乐
Nice one, Joy.
我喜欢恐龙那一次 很好笑
I like that time with the dinosaur. That was pretty funny.
等下 什么 怎么了?
Wait, what. What happened?
她对记忆做了手脚
She did something to the memory.
- 你做了什么?  - 我... 我只是碰了一下
- What did you do?  - I... I just touched it.
- 那应该没事啊  - 噢 把它变回来 乐乐
- That shouldn't make it change.  - Oh. Change it back, Joy.
- 我在试啊  - 变不回来吗?
- I'm trying.  - You can't change it back?
- 是的 好像不行  - 干得好 忧忧
- No. I guess I can't.  - Good going, Sadness.
现在只要莱莉回忆和老爸的那段时光 她就会悲伤 好极了
Now when Riley thinks of that moment with Dad, she's gonna feel sad. Bravo.
对不起 乐乐 我确实不知道 我想也许 假如你 我是说...
I'm sorry, Joy. I don't really know. I thought maybe if you, if you, I mean...
乐乐 有楼梯唉
Joy. We got a stairway coming up.
在我们弄清楚发生了什么之前 别再碰其它的记忆了
Just don't touch any other memories until we figured out what's going on.
- 好  - 可以了
- Okay.  - Alright.
准备好 这是怪物栏杆 我们要滑下去
Get ready. This is the monster railing and we are riding it all the way down.
等下 这是 又怎么了?
Wait, what. What happened?
- 核心记忆!  - 哦 不
- A core memory!  - Oh no.
- 忧忧 你干什么?  - 它看起来歪了
- Sadness, what're you doing?  - It looked like one was crooked
我就顺手打开 它就掉出来了 我...
So I opened it and it fell out. I...
呜呼!
Woo-hoo!
就是 我想 也许 触摸下
It's just that. I want to, maybe. hold one.
- 乐乐!  - 喔 喔 喔 喔
- Joy!  - Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
忧忧 你几乎碰了一个核心记忆
Sadness. You nearly touched a core memory.
你要是碰到了 我们就还原不了了
And when you touch them, we can't change them back.
哦 我知道 对不起 我有点问题了
Oh, I know. I'm sorry. Something's wrong with me.
我... 就好像濒临崩溃一样
I... It's like I'm having a break down.
你没有要崩溃 是压力太大了
You're not having a break down. It's stress.
我一直在犯那样的错误 太糟糕了
I keep making mistakes like that. I'm awful.
- 不 你没有  - 还有讨人厌
- No, you're not.  - And annoying.
他们 额... 你知道吗?
They, well... You know what?
你不能只关注错的地方
You can't focus on what's going wrong.
总有办法可以扭转局面
There's always a way to turn things around
重新找到乐趣
To find the fun.
嗯 找到乐趣 可我毫无头绪
Yeah, find the fun. I don't know how to do that.
好吧 嗯 想想有趣的事
Okay, well. Try to think of something funny.
哦 还记得那个喜剧吗 有只狗死了?
Oh. Remember the funny movie where the dog dies?
这 这不算... 欧
Oh, yeah. That's not... Oh.
和玛格在一起的那次?
What about that time, with Mag?
莱莉笑得太用力 牛奶都从鼻子里喷出来了
When Riley laughed so hard, milk came out of her nose.
笑一下嘛
Come on.
那个很痛苦 就像着火一样
Yeah, that hurts. It felt like fire.
- 好糟糕...  - 好吧 好吧
- It was awf...  - Okay, okay.
别想那个了 试试其他的
Don't think of that. Let's try something else.
- 你最喜欢干什么?  - 我最喜欢?
- What're your favorite things to do.  - My favorite?
我喜欢我们在外面的时候
Well, I like it when we're outside.
很好! 比如 海滩和阳光
That's good! Like, there's the beach and sunshine.
喔 比如那次我们把老爸的脖子以下埋在沙子里
Oh. Like the time we buried Dad in the sand up to his neck.
我更想念雨
I was thinking more like rain.
雨... 雨也是我的最爱!
Rain... Rain is my favorite too!
我们可以踩水坑
We can stomp around the puddles.
还有酷酷的雨伞 雷暴
You know. There's cool umbrellas, lightning storms.
更像是 雨水顺着我们的脊背淌下 浸湿鞋子
More like when the rain runs down our back, and makes our shoe soggy.
然后我们感到很冷 瑟瑟发抖 开始对一切事情都打不起精神
And we get all cold, shivery and everything starts feeling droopy.
噢 嘿 嘿 嘿 放轻松
Oh. Hey, hey, hey. Easy.
怎么哭了?
Why are you crying?
这... 这真是我们所追求目标的对立面
It's... It's really the opposite of what we're going for here.
哭泣帮助我放慢脚步 而不执着于生活中的困难
Crying helps me slow down and not obsessive with the way of life's problems.
你知道吗? 我们来想想其它的事情
You know what? Let's think about something else.
读读大脑手册怎么样? 听起来很有趣
How about we read some mind manuals? Sounds fun.
大部分我都读过了
I've read most of them.
那你读过这本吗? 看上去很有趣
Well. Have you read this one? This seems interesting.
长期记忆检索 第47卷
Long term memory retrieval. Volume 47.
- 没有  - 唔 这可是一本引人入胜的书
- No.  - Woo. A real page turner.
经由通道分组的长期记忆选择
Long term memory data selection via channels subgrouping.
看 很有趣吧 真是幸运儿
See. Fun already. Oh, you lucky dog.
你可以读这么酷的书 而我却要去工作 生活真是不公平
You're reading these cool things, I got to go work. Life is so unfair.
呃
Ugh.
我们该怎么办? 我们的资金只能维持一个月 或者两个
What can we do? We only got capital that'll last a month, maybe two.
如果那时还不能找到投资方 我们就得裁员了
If we can't find investors by then, we're gonna have to lay people off.
妈妈 爸爸 来和我说晚安
Mom. Dad. Come kiss me good night.
- 我知道 我知道  - 就过去
- I know. I know.   - Be right there.
我们得解决这事 好吗?
We got to land this, okay?
你们听到爸爸的话了吗? 他好像很沮丧
Did you hear Dad? He sounded really upset.
那是什么? 是熊吗? 是熊!
What was that? Was it a bear? It's a bear!
旧金山没有熊
There are no bears in San Francisco.
我见过一个毛发很浓密的家伙 他看起来就像熊
I saw a really hairy guy. He looked like a bear.
我太紧张了 我的神经很短
Oh. I'm so jumpy, my nerves are short.
呃 我不想听你神经的故事
Ew. I don't wanna hear about your nerves.
我告诉你们哪里出问题了吧 这次搬家就是个错误
I'll tell you what it is. This move has been a bust.
我一直都和你们这么说
That's what I've been telling you guys.
现在至少有37样东西让莱莉害怕了
There're at least 37 things for Riley to be scared of right now.
光是这个味道就能让她吐了
This smell alone is enough to make her gag.
真不敢相信妈妈爸爸搬到了这里
I can't believe Mom and Dad moved us here.
听着 我知道了 你们都有担心
Look. I get it. You guys have concerns.
但我们还经历过更糟的
But we've been through worst.
这样吧 我们列一个能让莱莉高兴的事情清单吧
Tell you what. Let's make a list of all the things Riley should be happy about.
好吧 我想想 房子很臭 房间也很臭
Fine. Let's see. This house stinks. Our room stinks.
- 比萨也很奇怪  - 我们的朋友们都不在这里
- Pizza is weird here.  - Our friends are back home.
我们的东西都在那辆丢失的搬运车里
And all our stuff is in the missing van.
振作点 还不是最糟糕
Oh, come on. It could be worse.
嗯 乐乐 我们可能会躺在脏兮兮的地板上 裹在睡袋里
Yeah, Joy. We could be lying on a dirty floor. In a bag.
好吧 我承认 我们的开头不是很顺利
Okay, I admit it. We had a rough start.
- 但想想好的事情吧...  - 不 乐乐
- But think of all the good things that...  - No, Joy.
现在莱莉根本高兴不起来
There is absolutely no reason for Riley to be happy right now.
让我们解决吧
Let us handle this.
我们明天把自己锁在卧室里然后逃学怎么样
I say we skip school tomorrow and lock ourselves in the bedroom.
我们没有干净衣服了 不能让别人看见我们
We have no clean clothes. I mean no one should see us.
我们可以嚎啕大哭
And we could cry until we can't breathe.
我们可以把门锁上 然后说我们知道的那句脏话
We should lock the door and scream that curse word we know.
- 挺好的一句话  - 等等
- It's a good one.  - Now, hold on.
听着 我们都有不开心的时候  但是...
Look. We all have our off days. You know...
嗨 甜心
Hi, honey.
妈妈牌坏消息火车驾到! 嘟嘟!
The Mom bad news Train is pulling in! Toot-toot!
还是找不到搬运车 唉
Still no moving van. Uh-huh.
他们现在又说可能星期二都不会到了 太差劲了
Now they're saying it won't be here till Tuesday. Can you believe it?
嘟 嘟 嘟
Toot-toot-toot.
- 爸爸呢?  - 在打电话
- Where's Dad?  - On the phone.
新的挑战让他每天都很忙
This new adventure is keeping him pretty busy.
瞧 我无需多说了
I rest my case.
你爸爸压力有点大 他在想怎么才能让新公司运转起来
Your dad is a little stressed, you know, about getting his new company up and running.
来点不高兴的表情吧
Now, for a few well placed withering scowls.
我现在想说的只有
I guess all I really want to say is
谢谢你
thank you.
尽管经历了这么多事情 你还是...
You know. Through all these confusion, you've stayed...
你还是这么开心
Well, you stayed our happy girl.
你爸爸压力很大
Your Dad is under a lot of pressure.
但如果你和我可以保持快乐的话 会对他帮助很大
But, if you and I can keep smiling, it would be a big help.
我们可以为他做到 对吧?
We can do that for him. Right?
哇
Whoa.
嗯
Well.
嗯 当然
Yeah. Sure.
能有你真是我们的荣幸
What did we do to deserve you?
- 好梦  - 晚安
- Sweet dreams.  - Good night.
你不能和妈妈争辩对吧
Well. You can't argue with Mom.
- 这就是幸福  - 不能和妈妈争辩 没错
- Happy it is.  - Can't argue with Mom, that's true.
- 乐乐队  - 不错
- Team Happy.  - Sounds great.
完全支持你 乐乐
Totally behind you, Joy.
我们准备睡觉了
Looks like we're going into REM.
我值夜班 我会把这些存放在长期记忆里
I've got dream duty so I'll take care of sending these to long term.
今天不错 伙计们 大家晚安 乐乐队
Great day today, guys. All sleep well, team Happy.
好了 今晚会有什么梦 造梦师?
Alright. What's on tonight, dream production?
就是这了 新家
Now. This is it. The new place.
和我一起住吧 莱莉
Come live with me, Riley.
- 有人点了西兰花比萨吗?  - 吃我吧 我是有机食物
- Somebody ordered a broccoli pizza?  - Eat me, I'm organic.
不 谁在下面负责编程啊?
No. Who is in charge of programming down there?
我知道我不应该这么做 但...
I know I'm not supposed to do this. But...
我们的一天不会这么结束的
We are not going to end the day like this.
不要担心
Don't you worry.
我会确保明天又将会是美好的一天
I'm going to make sure that tomorrow is another great day.
我保证
I promise.
- 早上好 我把你们吵醒了吗?  - 你一定要拉这个吗?
- Hello. Did I wake you?  - Do you have to play that?
我得练习啊
Well, I have to practice.
我觉得比起演奏这更像是拥抱
And I don't think of it as playing so much as hugging.
好 开学第一天 非常 非常 激动
Okay. First day of school. Very, very exciting.
我昨天熬夜制定了一个新计划 是这样
I was up late last night figuring out a new plan. Here it is.
- 怕怕 我需要一个清单  - 什么?
- Fear. I need a list  - What?
列出新学校开学第一天可能遇到的所有坏事
of all the possible negative outcomes on the first day at a new school.
早列好了 他们不会注意到没有流星的
Way ahead of you there. They won't notice no meteor.
厌厌 确保今天莱莉会非常惹眼
Disgust. Make sure Riley stands out today.
但还要合群
But, also blends in.
当我完工时 莱莉会非常漂亮的
When I'm through, Riley will look so good,
别的孩子会看他们自己的衣服然后自愧不如
the other kids will look at their own outfits and barf.
乐乐 对 乐乐 你负责控制台
Joy. Yes, Joy. You'll be in charge of the console.
让莱莉一整天保持开心
Keeping Riley happy all day long.
我想说 我喜欢你的裙子 太可爱了
And may I add, I love your dress, it's adorable.
哦 这个旧东西吗? 非常感谢 我喜欢它旋转时的样子
Oh, this old thing? Thank you so much. I love the way it twirls.
思想火车 准时到达
Train of Thought, right on schedule.
怒怒 把白日梦卸下来
Anger. Unload the daydreams.
我多订了一些 以防万一
I ordered extra, in case things get slow in class.
我猜用得着 如果新学校上的课很无聊没用的话
Might come in handy. If this new school is full of boring, useless classes.
很有可能
Which it probably will be.
哦 忧忧 有个超级重要的工作 非你莫属
Oh, Sadness. I've a super important job just for you.
- 真的吗?  - 嗯 跟我来
- Really?  - Uh-huh. Follow me.
- 你在干什么?  - 好嘞 完美
- What are you doing?  - And there. Perfect.
这是悲伤之圈
This is the circle of sadness.
你要做的就是确保所有的悲伤都待在圈里
Your job is to make sure that all the sadness stays inside of it.
所以说你想让我就站在这?
So, you want me just to stand here?
嘿 你的工作我不该指手画脚
Hey, it's not my place to tell you how to do your job.
只要确保
Just make sure that
所有的悲伤都待在圈里
all the sadness stays in the circle.
看到了吗? 你很擅长呢! 很好玩吧?
See? You're a pro at this! Isn't this fun?
- 不  - 好样的
- No.  - Attagirl.
好了大伙 新的开始
Alright everyone, fresh start.
我们将要有美好的一天 然后会变成美好的一周
We're going to have a good day which will turn into a good week,
然后是美好的一年 最后就是美好的一生!
which will turn into a good year, which will turn into a good life!
今天很特别 新学校 新同学
So, big day. New school. New friends.
我知道 我有些紧张但我更兴奋
I know. I'm kind of nervous but I'm mostly excited.
- 我看起来怎么样? 你喜欢我的袜子吗?  - 非常可爱
- How do I look? Do you like my socks?  - Very cute.
你一个人行吗? 想让我们陪你去吗?
You're gonna be okay? You want us to walk with you?
妈妈爸爸 和我们出现在公众场合? 不 谢谢
Mom and Dad, with us in public? No, thank you.
好 我来
Yup, I'm on it.
不用了 我行的 再见妈妈 再见爸爸
Nope, I'm fine. Bye Mom. Bye Dad.
祝你一天开心 小猴子
Have a good day in school, monkey.
祝你一天开心 甜心
Have a great day, sweetheart.
- 你确定我们要这么做吗?  - 对
- Are you sure we want to do this?  - In we go.
好 进去 对!
Okay, going in. Yes!
嗯 两点钟方向有一群酷女孩
Okay. We've got a group of cool girls at 2 o'clock.
- 你怎么知道?  - 两个耳洞 围脖
- How do you know?  - Double ears pierced. Infinity scarf.
- 哇 她抹了眼影吗?  - 对 我们要和她们做朋友
- Whoa. Is she wearing eye shadow?  - Yeah. We want to be friends with them.
- 和她们说话吧  - 你疯了吗?
- Let's go talk to them.  - Are you kidding?
我们不会和她们说话的 要让她们喜欢我们
We're not talking to them. We want them to like us.
哦... 对啊 等等 什么?
Oh... yeah. Wait.  What?
潜在的灾难已经基本整理完了
Almost finished with the potential disasters.
最糟糕的情况就是流沙 或者自燃
Worst scenario is either quicksands, spontaneous combustion
或者被老师点名 只要其中任何一件都没有发生...
or getting called on by the teacher. As long as none of those happens...
好了 同学们 今天我们班来了一个新同学
Okay, everybody. We have a new student in class today.
你逗我呢! 过时了? 这不可能!
Are you kidding me! Out of the days? This is not happening!
莱莉 想给大家介绍一下你自己吗?
Riley, would you like to tell us something about yourself?
不要! 假装我们不会说英语
No! Pretend we can't speak English.
别担心 我能搞定
Don't worry. I got this.
好吧
Okay.
我叫莱莉・安德森
My name is Riley Anderson.
我来自明尼苏达州 现在住在这里
I'm from Minnesota and now I live here.
明尼苏达州怎么样?
And how about Minnesota?
能给我们讲讲吗?
Can you tell us something about it?
你们那边的雪肯定比这里的大多了
Well you certainly get a lot more snow than we do.
哈哈哈 她太幽默了
Ha-ha-ha. She's hilarious.
嗯 冬天非常冷
Yeah, it gets pretty cold.
湖会结冰 到那时我们就会打冰球
The lake freezes over. And that's when we play hockey.
我在一个很厉害的队里 叫做土拨鼠队
I'm on a great team. We're called the Prairie dogs.
我的朋友玛格是前锋 我爸爸是教练
My friend, Mag, plays forward and my dad's the coach.
基本上我家每个人都会滑冰
Pretty much everyone in my family skates.
这也算是家庭传统了吧
It's kind of a family tradition.
我们每周末都去湖边玩
We go out on the lake almost every weekend.
以前是这样 直到...
Or, we did. Till...
我搬走了
I moved away.
- 嘿 这又是怎么了?  - 什么?
- Hey. What gives?  - What?
忧忧 你摸了一个记忆球?
Hey, Sadness. You touched a memory?
- 我之前和你说过的  - 哦 对 想起来了 我很抱歉
- We talked about this.  - Oh yeah, I know. I'm sorry.
回你的圆圈里去
Get back in your circle.
啊 这是怎么回事?
Ah. What's going on?
- 把这段记忆弄走啊 乐乐  - 弹出
- Get it out of there, Joy.  - Eject.
我们以前经常玩捉人还有别的游戏
We used to play tag and stuff.
三点钟方向酷学生在小声嘀咕
Cool kids whispering at 3 o'clock.
看到她们的表情了吗? 他们在评论我们
Did you see that look? They're judging us.
谁来帮我把这个东西拿下来 大家加...
Somebody help grab that thing. Everybody put in...
但现在 一切都不同了
But, everything is different now.
自从我们搬走以后
Since we moved.
哦 不 我们在哭
Oh no. We're crying and sloth.
什么? 忧忧 你在干什么呢!
What? Sadness, what are you doing!
哦 我很抱歉 我
Oh, I'm sorry. I'm, oh.
- 那是个核心记忆啊  - 但它是蓝的
- It's a core memory.  - But, it's blue.
不! 等等!
No! Wait!
停下! 不要
Stop it! No.
不要啊
No.
乐乐 不要
Joy. No.
- 那是个核心记忆啊  - 嘿!
- That's a core memory.  - Hey!
- 快放手  - 不要 等等
- Stop it.  Let go.  - Don't.  Wait.
核心记忆掉出来了!
The core memories!
啊!
Aw!
不要啊...
No-no-no...
- 啊!  - 啊!
- Aw!  - Aw!
谢谢你 莱莉
Thank you, Riley.
我知道搬去一个新地方很不容易
I know it can be tough moving to a new place.
但我们很高兴能在这里见到你
But we are happy to have you here.
好 同学们 拿出历史书来
Alright everyone. Get out you history books.
翻到第七章
And turn to chapter 7.
我现在可以说那句脏话了吗?
Can I say that curse word now?
- 呃  - 啊!
- Eh.  - Ah!
哦 不 一个 两个 三个 好了
Oh no. 1, 2, 3, okay.
还不够 什么?
Not enough. What?
我们在哪?
Where are we?
长期记忆? 等等
Long term memory? Wait.
嬉戏岛?
Goofball Island?
莱莉所有的个性之岛 都失联了
Riley's islands of personality, they're all down.
哦 太糟了
Oh, this is bad.
我... 我们可以搞定的
We... We can fix this.
我们只需要返回总部
We just have to get back to Headquarters,
把核心记忆放进去 莱莉就恢复正常了
plug the core memories in and Riley will be back to normal.
哦 莱莉没有核心记忆
Oh. Riley has no core memories
没有个性之岛 还没有... 哦
no personality islands and no... Oh.
- 什么? 怎么了?  - 你
- What? What is it?  - You.
你不在总部 没有你莱莉不可能开心的
You're not in Headquarters. Without you, Riley can't be happy.
我们得把你送回上面去
We got to get you back up there.
我来了 莱莉
I'm coming, Riley.
最后 我发现绿色的垃圾箱不是装可回收垃圾的
So, as it turns out the green trash can is not recycling,
是回收厨房垃圾的 比如堆肥和蛋壳
it's for greens, like compost and egg shells.
蓝色的才能装可回收垃圾 黑的是装正常垃圾的
And the blue one is recycling. And the black one is trash.
莱莉表现的很古怪啊 为什么?
Riley is acting so weird. Why is she acting so weird?
你还想要什么? 所有的岛屿都失联了
What did you expect? All the islands are down.
- 乐乐知道该怎么办  - 没错
- Joy would know what to do.  - That's it.
在她回来之前 我们就做乐乐会做的事吧
Until she gets back, we just do what Joy would do.
好主意 怒怒 怕怕 厌厌
Great idea. Anger, Fear, Disgust.
我们怎么可能高兴? 对吗
How are we supposed to be happy? Huh.
莱莉 我有个好消息
Hey, Riley. I've got good news.
我找到一个青年冰球联盟 就在旧金山
I found a junior hockey league, right here, in San Francisco.
听听这个 选拔赛就在明天下午放学后 多幸运啊 不是吗?
And get this, try-outs are tomorrow after school. What luck, right?
- 冰球?  - 哦 我们该怎么做?
- Hockey?  - Oh oh. What do we do?
伙计们... 这... 你来假装是乐乐
Guys...th... this... Here, you pretend to be Joy.
又能回到冰上玩你是不是很高兴呢?
Wouldn't it be great to be back out on the ice?
哦 当然 太棒了
Oh, yeah. That sounds fantastic.
这算什么? 根本不像乐乐啊
What was that? That wasn't anything like Joy.
- 啊... 因为我不是乐乐啊  - 废话
- Ah... because I'm not Joy.  - Yeah, no kidding.
你们发现这个问题了吗?
Did you guys pick up on that?
- 当然  - 对啊
- Sure.  - Oh yeah.
- 出了些差错  - 直接问她吗?
- Something's wrong.  - Should we ask her?
旁敲侧击一下 不要太明显而让她发现
Let's probe, but keep it subtle so she doesn't notice.
那么 开学第一天怎么样?
So. How was the first day of school?
- 她在旁敲侧击  - 我不干了
- She's probing us.  - I'm done.
- 你来假装乐乐  - 什么?
- You pretend to be Joy.  - What?
好 嗯...
Okay. Um...
挺不错吧 我猜 我不知道
It was fine, I guess. I don't know.
哦 非常棒 简直和乐乐一样
Oh, very smooth. That was just like Joy.
一定发生了什么
Something is definitely going on.
她之前从来不会这样 我们应该怎么做?
She's never acted like this before. What should we do?
我们得找出发生了什么
We're going to find out what's happening.
但我们需要帮助 向丈夫使眼色
But we'll need support. Signal the husband.
一个妙传到了里德那里
What a nice pass, over to Reed.
哦 不 她在看我们
Oh oh. She's looking at us.
- 她刚才说了什么?  - 什么?
- What did she say?  - What?
不好意思 长官 没人在听
Oh, sorry sir. No one was listening.
是今晚来收垃圾吗? 我们没盖马桶盖
Isn't it garbage night? We left the toilet seat up.
什么? 到底是什么? 女人? 什么?
What? What is it, woman? What?
- 他又是那个傻傻的表情  - 我能把他掐死
- He's making that stupid face again.  - I could strangle him right now.
再使一个眼色
Signal him again.
啊 嗯
Ah. So.
莱莉 学校怎么样?
Riley, how was school?
- 啊 简直是浪费时间  - 不是吧?
- Aw. Waste of time.  - Seriously?
你逗我呢
You got to be kidding me.
为了他 我们抛下了那个巴西直升机飞行员?
For this, we gave up that Brazilian helicopter pilot?
闪开! 我来当乐乐
Move! I'll be joy.
学校很好 好吗?
School was great. Alright?
莱莉 一切都好吗?
Riley. Is everything okay?
长官 她对我们翻白眼了
Sir, she just rolled her eyes at us.
她什么意思?
What is her deal?
好吧 先凶一点 我还不想用终极武器
Alright, make a show of force. I don't want to have to put the foot down.
不 不要用终极武器啊
No. Not the foot.
莱莉 我很不喜欢你现在的态度
Riley, I do not like this new attitude.
哦 我让你看看什么叫态度 老头子
Oh. I'll show you attitude, old man.
别别别 保持快乐
No-no-no-no. Stay happy.
你怎么回事? 就不能让我静静?
What is your problem? Just leave me alone.
长官 顶嘴指数很高了
Sir. Reporting high level of sass.
二级戒备状态
Take it to DEFCON 2.
你们也听到了 二级戒备状态
You heard that gentlemen. DEFCON 2.
听着 女儿 我不知道你这种无礼的态度是从哪里学来的
Listen, young lady. I don't know where this disrespectful attitude came from.
你想要更狠的吗 老爸 放马过来啊!
You want a piece of this, pops. Come and get it!
对啊 怎么了
Yeah.  Well. Well.
来吧 准备好武器
Here it comes. Prepare the foot.
开启安全闭锁状态
Keys, to safety position.
准备执行您的命令 长官
Ready to launch on your command, sir.
啊!
AHHH!
闭嘴!
Just, shut up!
开火!
Fire!
够了 回你的房间去
That's it. Go to your room.
现在!
Now!
发射成功 发射成功
The foot is down. The foot is down.
干的漂亮 伙计们 差点儿酿成灾难
Good job, gentlemen. That could've been a disaster.
真是场灾难啊
Well, that was a disaster.
来啊 和我一起飞 宝贝
Come. Fly with me, criancinha.
我们要从这上面 走过去吗?
We're gonna walk out there, on that?
这是回去最快的路
It's the quickest way back.
但它下面就是记忆垃圾场 掉下去就再也上不来了
But it's right over the Memory Dump. If we fall, we'll be forgotten forever.
为了莱莉 我们必须这么做
We have to do this for Riley.
跟着我走好了
Just follow my footsteps.
其实没那么高 根本... 啊
Not that high. It's totally... Ah.
哇
Wooah.
嘿
Hey.
那...
So...
刚才楼下情绪有点失控
Things got a little out of hand downstairs.
想谈一下吗?
Do you wanna talk about it?
来嘛 我那快乐的女孩儿在哪里呢?
Come on. Where's my happy girl?
猴子 呜呜呜
Monkey. Woo-hoo.
哇! 他想启动嬉戏岛
Whoa! He's trying to start up Goofball.
来嘛 呜呜呜
Come on. Hoo hoo-Haa haa.
忧忧! 快回头!
Sadness! Turn right back!
怎么回事?
What the?
我明白了 你需要独处时间
I get it. You need some alone time.
咱们以后聊吧
And we'll talk later.
- 我们有大麻烦了  - 乐乐 你在哪里?
- We have a major problem.  - Oh, Joy. Where are you?
嬉戏岛没了
We lost Goofball Island.
这意味她可能失去友情岛 冰球岛 诚实岛和亲情岛
That means she can lose Friendship and Hockey and Honesty and Family.
你可以解决这个问题 对吗 乐乐?
You can fix this. Right, Joy?
- 我... 我不知道  - 哦
- I... I don't know.  - Oh.
但是 我们一定要试试 来吧
But we have to try. Okay, come on.
- 莱莉睡着了  - 哎呀呀
- Riley's gone to sleep.  - Oh.
想起来... 这其实是个好事
Which is a good thing If... When you think about it.
她睡着了那就没有什么坏事情会发生
Because nothing else bad can happen when she's asleep.
她醒来之前我们会回到总部
We'll be back to Headquarters before she wakes up.
我们只要去对面的友情岛
We'll just go across Friendship Island.
- 哦 我们去不了  - 不不不...
- Oh, we'll never make it.  - No-no-no...
不要执着于生活中的困难
Don't obsess over the way of life's problems.
回忆下狗死了的那部喜剧电影
Remember the funny movie where the dog dies.
哦 忧忧 我们没有时间了
Oh Sadness. We don't have time for this.
我们只能绕道
We'll just have to go around.
走风景路线
Take the scenic route.
等等 乐乐 你会迷路的
Wait. Joy, you can get lost in there.
- 往积极方面想  - 好吧
- Think positive.  - Okay.
我积极地认为你会迷路
I'm positive you will get lost in there.
那是长期记忆
That's long term memory.
走廊和架子多得没有尽头
An endless swarm of corridors and shelves.
我在手册中读过
I read about it in the manuals.
手册? 手册
The manuals? The manuals.
- 你读过手册  - 是啊
- You read the manuals.  - Yeah.
那你应该知道怎样回到总部
So you know the way back to headquarters.
- 我想是吧  - 耶!
- I guess.  - Woo-hmm!
你就是我的地图
You are my map.
我们走吧 带路 我的地图
Let's go. Lead on, my map.
- 告诉我怎么走  - 好吧 我只是
- Show me where we're going.  - Okay, only.
太伤心走不了
I'm too sad to walk.
只要给我几个小时...
Just give me a few hours to...
- 哪条路 左边?  - 有
- Which way, left?  - Right.
不对 我的意思是走左边 我说了"有"是指"没错"
No, I mean go left. I said left was right like correct.
好吧
Okay.
其实这样感觉不错呀
This actually feels kind of nice.
好了 我们走啦 天亮前我们会回到总部
Okay, here we go. We'll be back to Headquarters before morning.
我们做得到的 不难做到!
We can do it. This will be easy!
这样可行
This is working.
行不通啊
This is not working.
- 快到了吗?  - 快了 只要再右转一下
- Are we getting close?  - Yeah. Just another right.
然后左转 然后再左转 再右转
And a left. And then another left and a right.
你确定知道路?
Are you sure you know where we're going?
好像咱们离总部越来越远
'Cause we seem to be walking away from Headquarters.
哎 莱莉醒了
Oh. Riley's awake.
哦 哦 哦
Oh. Oh. uh.
不要 不要去摸 记得吗?
Don't. Don't touch, remember?
如果你去摸 这些就会变伤心
If you touch them, they stay sad.
哦 抱歉 我... 我不摸
Oh. Sorry. I... I won't.
- 从现在开始  - 我快受不了了
- Starting now.  - I can't take much more of this.
忘记这些!
Forget them!
- 记忆工人?  - 但是 乐乐 我们差不多 哦
- Mind workers.  - But, Joy, we're almost oh.
- 电话号码  - 哦
- Phone numbers.  - Oh.
不需要这些 她手机里存了
We don't need all these. They're in her phone.
- 把它们都忘掉  - 劳驾? 嗨
- Just forget all that, please.  - Excuse me. Hi.
忘了它!
Forget it!
- 我想去友情岛  - 看这 四年的钢琴课
- I need to find Friendship Island.  - Look at this. 4 years of piano lessons.
是啊 记忆看起来模糊了
Yeah. It looks pretty faded.
这样吧 保留曲子"筷子"和"全心全意" 剩下的丢掉
You know what. Save Chopsticks and Heart and Soul, get rid of the rest.
- 你们是  - 美国总统 怎么处理?
- Are you.  - US presidents. What do you think?
只保留华盛顿 林肯和那个胖子
Just keep Washington, Lincoln and the fat one.
- 忘掉他们!  - 嘿!
- Forget them! - Hey!
你们不能把这些扔了 那都是非常美好的回忆
You can't throw those away. Those are perfectly good memories.
每个甜心公主娃娃的名字?
The names of every Cutiepie princess doll?
是啊 那都是关键信息
Yes. That is critical information.
- 闪烁风暴 蜂蜜裤子...  - 忘记它们!
- Glitter storm, Honey pants...  - Forget them!
- 嘿! 把那些调回来  - 它们都去垃圾场了
- Hey! Bring those back.  - They're in the Dump.
- 去了垃圾场就回不来了  - 是啊 小姐 这是我们的工作啊
- Nothing comes back from the Dump.  - Yeah. Look, lady. This is our job, okay.
莱莉要是对某个记忆不再关心 它就会模糊掉
When Riley doesn't care about a memory, it fades.
- 模糊?  - 都这样
- Fades?  - Happens to the best of them.
除了这个坏宝贝 这个永远不会模糊
Except for this bad boy. This one will never fade.
那个口香糖广告歌曲?
The song from the gum commercial?
有时我们会心血来潮 把那歌曲发到总部
You know. Sometimes we send that one up to Headquarters for no reason.
它就会在莱莉的脑袋里播了一遍又一遍 一百万遍
It just plays in Riley's head over and over again like a million times.
我们再看一遍吧
Let's watch it again.
我知道 我们都知道这首歌 好啦 是挺好记的
Yeah, I know. We all know the song. Okay, real catchy.
- 嘿 怎么样 要不要发过去?  - 好啊
- Hey. What do you think, should we do it?  - Yeah.
好 发过去! 哈哈
Okay. Here we go! Ha-ha-ha.
什么? 又是这个?
What the? This again?
啊 太好了
Ah. Great.
等一下! 你们知道怎么去友情岛吗!
Wait! Do you know how to get to Friendship Island!
你喜欢那里吗? 有感觉到地震没?
Do you like it there? Did you feel any earthquakes?
那桥酷吗?
Is the bridge cool?
嗯 挺好 那季后赛如何了?
Yeah, it's good. What happened with the playoffs?
我们赢了第一场比赛 教练说 我们或许可以参加今年的总决赛
We won the first game. Coach says we might actually go to the finals this year.
哦 我们球队新来了个女孩 她太酷了
Oh, and we got this new girl on the team. She's so cool.
- 呃 她说什么来着?  - 新来的女孩?
- Uh. She did not just say that.  - A new girl?
取而代之! 再也不需要莱莉
玛格已经有新朋友了?
Mag has a new friend already?
嘿嘿 保持快乐
Hey-hey. Stay happy.
我们不能再失掉别的岛屿了 伙伴们
We do not want to lose any more islands here, guys.
我们闭着眼也可以互传冰球
We can pass the puck to each other without even looking.
好像能参透对方心思
It's like mind reading.
你喜欢参透别人心思 玛格
You like to read minds, Mag.
- 我让你参透参透这个 - 怒怒 什么?
- I got something for you to read.  - Anger. What?
- 就在这儿!  - 等等 等等 冷静一下下
- Right here! - Wait-wait-wait. Let's just be calm for 1 second.
啊!
Ahh!
- 我得下了  - 什么?
- I got to go.  - What?
我得下了
I got to go.
等等 好 你们能不能就告诉我往哪边走?
Wait. Okay. Could you just please tell me which way is?
不好了
Oh no.
友情岛 怎么了?
Friendship Island. What?
不要啊
Not Friendship.
莱莉喜欢的 现在没了
Oh, Riley loved that one. And now it's gone.
送走友情 迎来寂寞
Goodbye Friendship Hello Loneliness.
我们只能走那条远路
We'll just have to go the long way.
是啊 很远很远很远很远的路
Yeah. The long long long long way.
我准备好了
I'm ready.
肯定有条更好的路线
There's got to be a better way.
- 呜 看看你  - 咦?
- Woo. We'll look at you.  - Huh?
我要选你而不是你
I will take you but not you.
哦! 我在跟谁开玩笑 我不能留你在这里
Oh! Who am I kidding? I can't leave you.
你好!
Hello!
- 哇!  - 等等 嘿 等等
- Wah! - Wait. Hey, wait.
哇 等等 停下
Whoa, wait. Stop.
我问下
Excuse me.
哦 我在 我在
Oh. I was, I was looking for
- 分你的心!  - 什么?
- diversion! - What?
哈哈! 再见 傻蛋
Ha ha! So long, sucker.
- 噢 我全身受伤了  - 等一下 我认识你
- Ow. I'm hurt all over.  - Wait, I know you.
不 不认识 很多人都说认识
No, you don't. I get that a lot.
- 我长个大众脸  - 不 不 不... 我确实认识
- I look like a lot of people.  - No no no... I do.
冰棒 莱莉的假想朋友
Bing Bong, Riley's imaginary friend.
- 你真的认识我吗?  - 当然
- You really do know me?  - Of course.
莱莉喜欢跟你玩 你们俩曾经是最好的朋友
Riley loved playing with you. You two were best friends.
哦 哦 你不会知道的
Oh, oh. You wouldn't know.
- 我们要回总部  - 总部?
- We're trying to get back to Headquarters.  - Headquarters?
- 你们是从总部来的?  - 是耶
- You guys are from Headquarters?  - Well, yeah.
我是乐乐 这是忧忧
I'm Joy. This is Sadness.
- 你是乐乐 那个乐乐?  - 嗯
- You're Joy, the Joy?  - Uh-huh.
那你们到底在这里干什么?
What the heck are you doing out here?
这是个很好的问题 忧忧 你要回答这个问题吗?
That's a good question. You want to answer that, Sadness?
没有你 我永远不会快乐
Without you, I won't ever be happy.
我不想不快乐 得帮你回去
We can't have that. We got to get you back.
这样吧 跟我来
I'll tell you what. Follow me.
谢谢 见到你太高兴了
Thank you. It is so great to see you again.
我想跟你说 我太赞赏你的工作了
I got to tell you. I'm such a huge fan of your work.
你还记得你和莱莉组成了乐队吗?
Do you remember when you and Riley were in a band?
哈哈 我参加了你们所有的音乐会
Ha-ha-ha. I went to all of your concerts.
是啊 我吹鼻子吹得不好
Yeah. I blow a mean nose.
- 看你玩捉人游戏是一种享受  - 2次房间冠军
- Watching you play tag was such a treat.  - 2 time room champ.
- 哦 还记得玩火箭  - 当然 火箭的动力来源是歌曲
- Oh, and remember your rockets.  - Of course, it runs on song power.
对 你的主题曲
That's right. Your theme song.
- 你最爱玩的伙伴是谁?  - 冰棒 冰棒
- Who's your friend who likes to play?  - Bing Bong. Bing Bong.
- 他的火箭让你欢呼"万岁!"  - 冰棒 冰棒
- His rocket makes you yell "Hooray!"  - Bing Bong. Bing Bong.
你到底是什么?
What exactly are you supposed to be?
这个难搞懂 我主要是棉花糖 但是
You know what's unclear? I'm mostly cotton candy. But.
形状上来讲 我像猫 像大象 又像海豚
Shape wise. I'm part cat, part elephant, part dolphin.
海豚?
Dolphin?
你记得吧? 莱莉三岁时 流行模仿动物叫声
You got to remember. When Riley was 3, animals were all the rage.
牛哞哞叫 马嘶鸣
The cow goes moo. The horse goes neigh.
当时所有的人都在模仿
It's all people talked back then.
是啊 是啊 应该是的 你在这里干什么?
Yeah, yeah. I guess that's true. What are you doing out here?
最近她对假想的朋友没有什么需求
Well. There's not much call for imaginary friends lately.
所以 我...
So, I.... You know.
嘿 嘿 别难过
Hey. Hey. Don't be sad.
这样吧 我回到总部
Tell you what. When I get back up to Headquarters,
我会确保让莱莉记得你
I'll make sure Riley remembers you.
- 真的?  - 当然 她喜欢的
- You will?  - Of course. She loved that.
哈哈! 这是我一生中最开心的一天
Ha-ha! This is the greatest day of my life.
嗷... 呜呜!
Ow ow ow... Ow!
- 你还好吗?  - 嘿 这是怎么回事?
- Are you okay?  - Hey, what's going on?
我哭的话会哭出糖果
I cry candy.
- 尝下焦糖 很美味  - 呜呜呜
- Try the caramel, it's delicious.  - Woo.
- 哇!  - 呜
- Whoa! - Woo.
- 用这个  - 谢谢
- Here, use this.  - Thanks.
哦 等等 等一下
Oh, hold on. Wait a second.
它老是卡在底部
It always gets stuck at the bottom.
放这里
Here.
怎么了? 这是假想的
What? It's imaginary.
谢谢 这样可以更方便我们走回总部
Thanks. This will make it a lot easier to walk back to Headquarters.
走路吗? 我们不用走路
Walk? We're not walking.
我们可以坐思想火车
We're taking the Train of Thought.
火车 我怎么没想到
The Train. Of course.
这样就快多啦 但是 我们怎样赶上火车呢?
That is so much faster. But how do we catch it?
火车到处跑 不过想象地里有一站
Well, it kind of goes all over the place but there is a station in Imagination Land.
我知道捷径 来吧 这边
I know a shortcut. Come on, this way.
我很高兴遇到了你
Oh. I'm so glad we ran into you.
火车站就在这里面 您先请
The station is right in here. After you.
- 乐乐  - 什么?
- Joy.  - What?
我在手册里读过这地方 我们不应该去那里
Well. I read about this place in the manual. We shouldn't go in there.
冰棒说 这是去总部的最快捷径
Bing Bong says it's the quickest way to Headquarters.
不可以 乐乐 这个是抽象思维
No. But Joy, this is abstract thought.
你在胡说什么? 我经常去里面
What are you talking about? I go in here all the time.
是捷径 你看
It's a shortcut. You see.
劫难的劫 境地的境 捷径
D-A-N-G-E-R. Shortcut.
危险 勿进!
劫难的劫 境地的境 捷径
D-A-N-G-E-R. Shortcut.
危险 勿进!
我证明给你们看
I'll prove it to you.
看我
Look at me.
我向车站穿过去 因为我在走捷径
I'm crossing to the station. 'Cause I'm taking the shortcut.
咱们绕道吧 这边走
Let's-Let's go around. This way.
差不多到了
Almost there.
如果你要绕远路 你去吧
If you want to walk the long way, go for it.
但是莱莉需要快乐 我不想错过那趟火车
But Riley needs to be happy. I'm not missing that Train.
冰棒知道怎样做 他有一部分是海豚 海豚很聪明
Bing Bong knows what he is doing. He's part dolphin, they're very smart.
好吧 或许
Well, I guess.
好 今天要理解什么抽象概念?
Okay. What abstract concept are we trying to comprehend today?
- 孤独  - 嗯
- Loneliness.  - Hm.
好像里面有东西
Looks like there is something in there.
开动一分钟 把脏东西烧光光
I'm going to turn it on for a minute and burn out the gunk.
我告诉过你们 很快就会回到总部
What did I tell ya? You'll be in Headquarters in no time.
- 哇  - 嘿 你们看!
- Whoa.  - Hey, will you look at that?
- 哇 怎么回事?  - 不好 他们打开开关了
- Whoa. What's happening?  - Oh no, they turned it on.
哈 以前从未见过这个
Ha. Never seen this before.
我的脸 我漂亮的脸 哇!
My face. My beautiful face. Whoa!
- 到底是怎么回事?  - 我们正在抽象化
- What is going on?  - We're abstracting.
有四个阶段 这是第一个
There are 4 stages. This is the first.
非客观碎片化
Non-objective fragmentation.
好了 不要惊慌 最重要的是 我们一起 一个不落下
Alright, do not panic. What is important is that we all stay together.
- 哦  - 哇
- Oh.  - Aw.
我们正处在第二阶段 正在解构
We're in the second stage. We're deconstructing.
跑!
Run!
啊 我的腿啊 不见了
Aw. I can't feel my legs.
- 哦 找到了  - 回来 我自己
- Oh, there they are.  - Come here, me.
趁我们还没失去形状和颜色 赶快离开这儿
We got to get out of here. Before we're not even shape and color.
大家会永远困在这里
We'll get stuck here forever.
冰棒 我们为什么跑这里来?
Bong. Why did we come in here?
我告诉你了 这是捷径
I told you. It's a shortcut.
火车
The Train.
不好了 我们变二维了 这是第三阶段
Oh no. We're 2 dimensional. That's stage 3.
- 我们走不动  - 死亡 不幸的死亡
- We're getting no where.  - Death. Unlucky death.
来吧
Come on.
我们进不去
We can't fit.
哦 不 我们象征化了 这是最后阶段
Oh no, we're not figurative. This is the last stage.
我们不能活着出去了
We're not gonna make it.
等等 我们是二维的 面朝下倒下
Wait, we're 2 dimensional. Fall on your face.
停 停!
Stop. Stop!
不 你不是说这是一条捷径吗
No. I thought you said that was a shortcut.
我说过 但是 哇 我们不该进去的
I did. But wow, we should not have gone in there.
好危险的 他们真应该立个警告牌
That was dangerous. They really should put up a sign.
- 下一趟火车要等多久?  - 谁晓得?
- How long till the next Train?  - Who knows?
不过别担心 还有另一个车站 那边
But don't worry. There's another station. That way.
火车在那儿一定会停的 然后直接去总部
The Train always stops there, right before it goes to Headquarters.
如果我们快点 就可以赶上
If we hurry, we can catch it.
该不会又是你所谓的捷径吧?
This isn't another one of your shortcuts, is it?
哈哈哈 是啊
Ha-ha-ha. Yeah.
- 难道真有另一站?  - 嗯 经过那里
- Is there really another station?  - Uh-huh. Through there.
- 欢迎光临想象地  - 想象地?
- Welcome to Imagination Land.  - Imagination Land?
当然 我经常来这里 几乎成市长了
Sure. I come here all the time. I'm practically the mayor.
嘿 你们饿了吗? 有炸薯条森林
Hey, you guys hungry? There's French Fries Forest.
哇塞! 哈哈哈
No way! Ha-ha-ha.
来看看 奖杯镇
Check it out. Trophy Town.
奖牌 勋带 人人都是赢家
Medals,  Ribbons. Everyone's a winner.
我荣获一等奖
I won first prize.
- 我也是!  - 哦 参与奖
- Me too! - Oh. Participation award.
等等 那是什么? 那...
Wait, is that? Is that a...
你看 这是白云镇
Look. It's Cloud Town.
这是我最喜欢的 哈哈
That's my favorite. Hoo-hoo-hoo.
- 哦 好软啊  - 哦 哦 哦 让我试试
- Oh, it's so soft.  - Oh oh oh. Let me try.
嘿! 你干啥呢?
Hey! What's the big idea?
你最好给我修复好墙壁 否则你有大麻烦了
You better fix that wall or else you're in big trouble.
哦 不会吧 熔岩 哇呼呼
Oh no, lava. Woo. Oh.
想象地 最棒了
Imagination Land is the best.
哦 为何一切都如此地互动?
Oh, is it all going to be so interactive?
嘿 瞧! 是纸牌屋
Hey look! The House of Cards.
等等 等一下
Woo wait. Hang on just a minute.
- 你的火箭  - 是啊
- Your rocket.  - Yeah.
我一直把它藏那里保存着
I stashed it in there for safekeeping.
现在我正好用它载莱莉到月球!
And now I'm all set to take Riley to the moon!
- 哦 对不起  - 干得好 哼
- Oh, I'm sorry.  - Great.
- 哇 我太喜欢想象地了  - 很棒吧?
- Whoa. I love Imagination Land.  - Isn't it great?
总有一些新东西 比如...
And there's always something new like...
- 那到底是谁?  - 假想出来的男朋友
- Who the heck is that?  - Imaginary boyfriend.
- 我会为莱莉去死  - 哇 哼
- I would die for Riley.  - Whoa, ewk.
- 哇 我之前从没见过他  - 我住在加拿大
- Wow. I've never seen him before.  - I live in Canada.
总之 这边 穿过学前世界 我们就离火车很近了
Anyway, this way, through Preschool World. We're nearly to the train.
莱莉 我们来了 呜呼 哈哈哈
Riley, here we come. Woo-Hoo. Ha-ha-ha.
应该会蛮有趣的 新队伍 新朋友
This should be fun. New team. New friends.
这些孩子看起来蛮厉害的
These kids looked pretty good.
毕竟他们来自旧金山啊 哈哈哈
Considering they're from San Francisco. Heh-heh-heh.
- 我走了  - 好 祝你好运 亲爱的
- Got to go.  - Okay. Good luck, sweetie.
现在有运气也没用了
Luck isn't going to help us now.
冰球岛已经摇摇欲坠了
If she tries to use Hockey Island, it's going down.
所以我找来了所有我能想起的冰球记忆
Which is why, I recalled every hockey memory I can think of.
总有一个可以替代核心记忆
One of these has got to work in place of a core memory.
- 她要上场了  - 快
- She's about to play. - Hurry.
哈哈 我们成功了 起作用了
Ha ha. We did it gang. It's working.
嗷
Oh.
就好像我们没学过一样
It's like we don't learn anything.
加油 射门
Go ahead and shoot it.
- 够了  - 别别别
- That's it. - No no no.
想想快乐的事
Free on your happy place.
- 莱莉 怎么了?  - 我们走
- Riley, what's wrong?  - Let's go.
- 你不打算打完选拔赛吗?  - 有什么意义?
- You're not going to finish try-outs?  - What's the point?
嘿 都会好起来的
Hey. It will be alright.
- 我们回去吧  - 别再说什么一切都会好起来了
- Let's just go back.  - Stop saying everything will be alright.
打得真好 姑娘们
Nice hustle, ladies.
冰球岛!
Hockey!
哦不不 她爱冰球
Oh no no. She loves hockey.
她不能放弃冰球
She can't give up hockey.
冰棒 我们得马上去坐火车
Bing Bong, we have to get to that station.
当然 这边 经过饼干大城堡就到了
Sure thing. This way, just past Grand Cracker Castle.
嘿 奇怪了
Hey. That's weird.
饼干大城堡之前就在这里 为什么他们要搬走它
Grand Cracker Castle used to be right here. I wonder why they moved it.
我发誓闪亮尖尖山之前就在这里的
I would have sworn Sparkle Pointy Mountain was right here.
- 到底怎么回事?  - 好吧 我也不知道
- Hey, what's going on?  - Yeah yeah. I don't know.
- 我们要回去了  - 公主梦想世界
- We'll have to come back.  - Princess Dreamworld.
噢 毛绒玩具名人殿
Oh, The Stuffed Animal Hall of Fame.
我的火箭!
My rocket!
等等 莱莉和我还要用这个火箭呢
Wait. Riley and I were still using that rocket.
里... 里面还剩下一些歌曲能量
It... It still has some song power left.
你最爱玩的伙伴是谁?
Who's your friend who likes to play?
不! 不要啊
No! No no no.
你们不能扔掉我的火箭 莱莉和我还要去月球呢
You can't take my rocket to the Dump. Riley and I are going to the moon.
莱莉不会和我绝交吧?
Riley can't be done with me?
嘿 没关系的 我们会有办法的
Hey, it's going to be okay. We can fix this.
只要我们回到总部 去火车站往哪走?
We just need to get back to Headquarters. Which way to the Train station?
我本来做好了全部的旅行计划
I had a whole trip planned for us.
嘿 谁最怕痒啊? 挠痒怪来啦
Hey, who's ticklish? Here comes the tickle monster.
嘿 冰棒 看这里
Hey. Bing Bong, look at this.
我们来玩个有趣的游戏吧 你指出火车站在哪
Oh, here's a fun game. You point to the Train station
然后我们走过去 是不是很好玩?
and we all go there. Won't that be fun?
快来 我们一起去火车站
Come on, let's go to the Train station.
很抱歉他们扔掉了你的火箭
I'm sorry they took your rocket.
他们夺走了你心爱的东西 它已经永远离你而去了
They took something that you loved. It's gone, forever.
- 忧忧 这会让他更难过的  - 对不起
- Sadness, don't make him feel worse.  - Sorry.
那是我和莱莉之间最后的记忆
It's all I had left of Riley.
我猜你和莱莉一定有过很精彩的冒险吧
I bet you and Riley had great adventures.
噢 相当精彩
Oh, they were wonderful.
有一次 我们穿越回过去 一天吃了两次早餐
Once, we flew back in time. We had breakfast twice that day.
- 忧忧  - 听起来好棒 莱莉一定很喜欢
- Sadness.  - It sounds amazing. I bet Riley liked it.
那当然 我们以前是最好的朋友
Oh, she did. We were best friends.
是的 真让人心疼
Yeah, it's sad.
搞什么?
What?
我好了
I'm okay now.
走吧 火车站在这边
Come on. The Train station is this way.
- 你怎么做到的?  - 我也不知道
- How did you do that?  - Oh, I don't know.
- 我很难过 所以听他...  - 嘿!
- I feel sad so I listen to what...  - Hey!
火车在这
There's the Train.
我们做到了 终于可以回去了
Oh, we made it. We're finally going to get home.
不是吧 这些事实和想法看起来都差不多嘛
Oh no. These facts and opinions look so similar.
别担心 一直都是这样的
Don't worry about it. Happens all the time.
从一到十打分的话 我给今天一个"F"
On a scale of 1 to 10, I give this day an 'F'.
所以我们不能就这么傻站着了 做点什么吧
Well, why don't we quit standing around and do something?
- 比如说呢? 天才  - 比如辞职 就像我现在这样
- Like what, genius?  - Like quitting. That's what I'm doing.
当然 只有懦夫才会临阵脱逃 但我会因此活下来
Sure. It's the coward's way out. But this coward is gonna survive.
情感是不能辞职的 天才
Emotions can't quit, genius.
好恶心 我们不是应该让莱莉一直开心吗
Ewkk. I thought we're supposed to be keeping Riley happy.
等一下 等一下!
Wait a minute. Wait a minute!
- 这是啥?  - 没什么
- What is it?  - Oh nothing.
- 只是一个棒呆了的点子  - 什么?
- Just the best idea ever.  - What?
所有美好的核心记忆都是在明尼苏达产生的
All the good core memories were made in Minnesota.
所以 我们回明尼苏达去制造更多这样的记忆
Ergo, we go back to Minnesota and make more.
- 如何!  - 等等
- Ta-dah!  - Wait wait wait.
你是说我们离家出走?
You're saying we run away?
别这么说嘛
Well, I wouldn't call it that.
我把它叫做"快乐核心记忆发展计划"
I call it the 'Happy core memory development program'.
- 你不是认真的吧  - 嘿 我们的生活本来是很完美的
- You can't be serious.  - Hey, our life was perfect.
直到爸妈决定搬到讨厌的旧金山来
Until Mom and Dad decided to move to San Fran stink town.
但 这也太疯狂了吧
But, I mean. It's just so drastic.
需要我提醒你之前有多美好吗
Need I remind you of how great things were there.
我们的房间 院子 还有朋友
Our room. Our backyard. Our friends.
我没说要口香糖广告!
Did I ask for the gum commercial?
不管怎么说 重点是以前比现在好
Anyway, it was better. That's my point.
- 也对 莱莉在明尼苏达过得很开心的  - 等等
- Yeah, Riley was happier in Minnesota.  - Wait. Hold on.
我们能否先睡一觉再议此事?
Should we just sleep on this or something?
好的 睡一觉
Fine, let's sleep on it.
因为我相信美好时光就在不远处等着我们
Because, hey, I'm sure joyly fun-filled times are just around the corner.
怎么了?
Huh?
嘿 嘿 为什么不走了?
Hey hey. Why aren't we moving?
莱莉睡了 我们下班了
Riley's gone to sleep. We're all on break.
你是说我们要被困到明天早上?
You mean we're stuck here until morning?
是的 她睡着的时候思想火车就会停下来
Yeah. The Train of Thought doesn't run while she's asleep.
- 不 我们等不了那么久  - 要不叫醒她吧?
- Oh, we can't wait that long.  - How about we wake her up?
忧忧 太可笑了 我们怎么可能... 噢
Sadness, that's ridiculous. How can we possibly... oh.
- 要不叫醒她吧?  - 好主意 乐乐
- How about we wake her up?  - Great idea, Joy.
多谢 走吧
Thanks, come on.
造梦工厂
哇 这地方真大
Whoa. This place is huge.
比我想象中的小多了
It looks so much smaller than I expected.
哇 我能飞 我喜欢这个
Wow, I can fly. I love that one.
彩虹独角兽 她就在这里
Rainbow Unicorn. She's right there.
我朋友说你很有名
My friend says you're famous.
- 她想要你签名  - 不 别闹 忧忧
- She wants your autograph.  - No no, Sadness.
别打扰独角兽小姐好吗?
Don't bother Miss. Unicorn, okay?
不好意思 她乡下来的 很尴尬 对吧?
Sorry she's from out of town. It's so embarrassing, right?
我喜欢你在梦游大冒险第七幕的表演 就这样再见 爱你哟
I love you in Fairy Dream Adventure part 7. Okay bye. I love you.
灯闪请勿入内
哈! 这上面啥意思? 管他呢 进去看看
Ha! Wonder what that means? Oh well, let's go in.
布置好教室场景
Set up the classroom set.
今天的记忆来了 我们有的忙了
Today's memories are in. We've got a lot to work with here.
莱莉抛弃了最好的朋友 在学校度过了糟糕的一天 并且放弃了冰球
Riley dumped her best friend, had a miserable day at school and quit hockey.
编剧们整了一个很棒的剧本
The writers had put together a killer script.
就因为乐乐和忧忧走了 我就得值天杀的梦境班
Just because Joy and Sadness are gone, I have the stupid dream duty.
好吧 我们怎样才能叫醒她?
Okay. How are we going to wake her up?
有时她做了噩梦就会吓醒
Well. She wakes up sometimes when she has a scary dream.
- 我们可以吓醒她  - 吓醒她?
- We could scare her.  - Scare her?
- 不 不要 她这一天过得够惨了  - 但是 乐乐
- No no. She's been through enough already.  - But, Joy.
忧忧 你有你的办法
Sadness, you may know your way around down here.
但我了解莱莉
But I know Riley.
我们要让她快乐 让她在愉悦中醒来
We're gonna make her so happy, she'll wake up with exhilaration.
- 我们让她从兴奋中醒来  - 这从来没有过啊
- We'll excite her awake.  - That's never happened before.
对 莱莉喜欢狗狗 穿上这个
Woo, Riley loves dogs. Put this on.
我觉得这样不行的
I don't think that will work.
- 冰棒  - 在
- Bing Bong.  - Yeah.
- 别让这些东西有事  - 明白
- Don't let anything happen to these.  - Got it.
嗯哼 加上现实扭曲滤镜
Uh-huh. Add the reality distortion filter.
很好 记住 每个人都对着摄像机
Love it. Remember, play to the camera everyone.
莱莉就是摄像机 其余的人赶紧走
Riley is the camera. Make them get out of there.
我们马上开始 五 四 三...
We are on in 5 4 3...
同学们好 在我们开始随堂测试前...
Hello class. Before we begin today's pop quiz...
演得真差劲
And she is one bad actress.
我想先介绍我们的新同学
I want to introduce our new student.
莱莉 你能站起来并且介绍一下...
Riley. Would you like to stand up and introduce...
- 镜头起  - 你自己吗?
- Camera up.  - yourself?
好 莱莉说台词
And, to Riley.
我叫莱莉・安德森
My name is Riley Anderson.
我来自明尼苏达州 现在住在这里
I'm from Minnesota and now I live here.
啊 快看 她牙齿掉了
Ew. Look, her teeth are falling out.
哎呀 真恶心
Ew, gross.
掉牙 好吧 早就习惯了
Teeth falling out. Yeah, I'm used to that one.
我猜猜 没穿裤子
Let me guess. We've no pants on.
嘿 快看 她没穿裤子就来学校啦
Hey, look. She came to school with no pants on.
一猜一个准!
Called it!
- 准备好了吗?  - 我觉得这种快乐的情节是叫不醒她的
- Ready?  - I don't think this happy thing is going to work.
- 但如果我们吓她  - 只管跟着我做
- But if we scare her.  - Just follow my lead.
走了
Here we go.
嗷呜 汪... 汪... 汪...
Ouuu. Bark... bark... bark...
- 那谁啊?  - 怎么回事?
- Who is that?  - What's going on?
沉睡 清醒
喂 该你上了
Psst, you're on. Go.
呜 来开派对 来跳舞啊 呜
Woo. Let's party. Let's dance. Woo.
原来是个派对
Hey. A party.
汪... 汪... 汪
Bark... bark... bark.
乐乐 这样没用的
Joy, this is not working.
不
No.
忧忧 你在做什么? 快回来
Sadness, what are you doing? Come back here.
这只是个梦 只是个梦 只是个梦
It's just a dream. It's just a dream. It's just a dream.
她们正在试图叫醒莱莉 叫保安
They're trying to wake her up. Call security.
- 好久不见 莱莉 是我啊  - 冰棒?
- Hi Riley, it's me.  - Bing Bong?
忧忧 你毁了这个梦
Sadness. You are ruining this dream.
- 你吓坏她了  - 但你看 起作用了
- You're scaring her.  - But look. It's working.
哇
Whoa.
她们不是这个梦的一部分 抓住她们
They're not part of this dream. Get them.
在原地别动!
Stop right there!
转过去 转过去
Pan away. Pan away.
哎哟 这什么鬼嘛
Boo. Pick a Pot line.
- 嗷 轻点啊  - 别乱动
- Aw, careful.  - Hold still.
你们不能这样 我总部有人
You can't do this. I know people in Headquarters.
不... 不... 不...
No... no... no...
核心记忆在他身上
There go the core memories.
别让我进去啊 我怕黑 求你了
Not in there. I'm scared of the dark, please.
走吧
Come on.
- 这是什么地方?  - 潜意识区
- What is this place?  - The subconscious.
他们把所有捣乱的都关在这
That's where they take all the troublemakers.
我感觉帽子有点松
My hat feels loose.
我们怎么进去?
How do we get in?
你拿了我的帽子还是...
You got my hat or...
- 这是你的帽子吗?  - 是的 这是我的帽子
- Is that your hat? - Yeah, it's my hat.
你确定? 给我看看标签
You sure? I don't know. Look at the label.
是的 写的是我的帽子
Yeah, it says my hat.
- 等等 上面写着"我的帽子"?  - 是我的啊 上面写着呢
- Wait. It says my hat?  - My hat, it says.
- 我在我帽子上就是这么写的  - 你在说什么呢?
- That's what I wrote in my hat.  - What are you talking about?
- 看吧 你戴的是我的帽子  - 好了 这是我的帽子
- Look. You got my hat on.  - Okay, it's my hat.
- 喂 你们干吗呢  - 啊 你抓到我们了
- Hey you.  - Oh, you caught us.
回里面去 别想逃跑
Get back in there. No escaping.
我不喜欢这里 这里保存的是莱莉最恐惧的记忆
I don't like it here. It's where they keep Riley's darkest fears.
是西兰花
It's broccoli.
这个楼梯通向地下室
The stairs to the basement.
奶奶的真空吸尘器 啊!
Grandma's vacuum cleaner. Ah!
好了 走吧
Okay, come on.
- 你走路能轻点吗?  - 我也想啊
- Would you walk quieter?  - I'm trying.
那怎么...
What is going...
糖果包装纸
Candy wrappers.
- 冰棒  - 乐乐?
- Bing Bong. - Joy?
- 原来你在这  - 嘘
- There you are.  - Shhh.
小丑
It's Jangles.
- 核心记忆在你这吗?  - 在这呢
- Do you have the core memories?  - Yeah.
他只在意糖果
All he cared about was the candy.
嘘
Shh.
我们得赶紧离开这里 去赶火车
We're outta here. Let's get to that Train.
等等 火车还是开不了 我们还是需要叫醒莱莉
Wait. The Train is not running. We still have to wake up Riley.
但怎么做呢?
But how?
哦 别啊
Oh no.
嘿 忧忧 你听说他们在办的那个派对吗?
Hey, Sadness. Did you hear about the party they were having?
是的乐乐 我听说了 是那个生... 生... 生日派对吧?
Yeah, yes Joy. Isn't it a bir... bir... birthday party?
你说生日派对?
Did you say birthday?
- 那里好多蛋糕和礼物  - 还有游戏和气球
- And there's going to be cake and presents. - And games and balloons.
生日派对!
A birthday!
是的 跟我们来
Okay. Follow us.
只有惊吓才能唤醒她 是这样吧?
Nothing like a good scare to wake you up, right?
- 好了 这是我的笔迹  - 不 才不是
- Okay, it's my hand writing.  - No, it isn't.
- 这是我的帽子 我写在上面了  - 才不是 这是我的帽子
- It's my hat. I wrote that.  - No, this one's my hat.
- 谁是派对公主?  - 啊!
- Who's the birthday girl?  - Aw!
- 耶!  - 好了 咱们走
- Woo-hoo.  - Come on, let's go.
- 哈哈 我们做到了  - 哈哈
- Ha ha. We made it. - Ha ha.
- 是谁正在回总部的路上呢  - 是我们!
- Guess who's on their way to Headquarters.  - We are!
- 怎么回事啊?  - 他又来了
- What is going on?  - He did it again.
我们在学校里 没穿裤子 还有一只狗
We were at school. And we were naked. And there was a dog.
它的后半段... 在... 在追它自己 我是说
The back half was... It was... It was chasing it, I mean.
- 还有冰棒  - 蠢货 这就是个梦而已
- There was a Bing Bong.  - You idiot. It was a dream.
太荒谬了 我们居然连觉都没法睡好了
This is ridiculous. We can't even get a good night's sleep anymore.
是时候行动了
Time to take action.
笨蛋爸妈 如果没有搬家
Stupid Mom and Dad. If they hadn't moved us,
什么事都不会发生
none of this would have happened.
谁赞同我?
Who's with me?
我... 我... 不不不...
I... I'm... no no no...
好 我们行动吧
Yeah. Let's do it.
她接受了 没有回头路了
She took it. There's no turning back.
那我们怎么回明尼苏达呢?
So. How are we going to get to Minnesota from here?
这样 我们可以去大象园租一头大象
Well. Why don't we go down to the elephant lot and rent an elephant?
哇 听起来好棒
Hey, that sounds nice.
我们坐大巴啦 白痴!
We're taking the bus, nitwit!
明天正好有辆大巴要走 完美
There is a bus leaving tomorrow, perfect.
车票是要花钱的 我们从哪弄到钱?
A ticket costs money. How do we get money?
- 妈妈的钱包  - 噢 不会吧
- Mom's purse.  - Oh. You wouldn't.
我必须得这样 我们上次见到它是在哪?
Oh, but I would. Where was it we saw it last?
- 不!  - 啊!
- No!  - Ah!
就在楼下的某个地方
It's downstairs somewhere.
是爸妈害我们这样的 必须要付出点代价
Mom and Dad got us into this mess. They can pay to get us out.
这个怎么样... 是不是很棒?
How about this... isn't this nice?
你从这可以看到所有东西
You can see everything from up here.
看 那里是归纳推理中心 那是似曾相识
Look. There's Inductive Reasoning. There's Deja Vu.
那是语言处理中心 那是似曾相识
There's Language Processing. There's Deja Vu.
那是批判思维中心 那是似曾相识
There's Critical Thinking. There's Deja Vu.
还有 快来看看她的记忆
And look at this guy's memories.
嘿 把莱莉吓醒
Hey. That was a good idea.
是个好主意
About scaring Riley awake.
- 你也不是那么糟糕嘛  - 真的吗?
- You're not so bad.  - Really?
干得好
Nice work.
我迫不及待想让以前的莱莉回来了
I can't wait to get the old Riley back.
只要我们一回到总部 就让一切回归正常
As soon as we get there, I'm going to fix this whole mess.
哇 这是莱莉吗?
Whoa. Is this Riley?
她都这么大了 那坐不进我的火箭里了
She's so big now. She won't fit in my rocket.
我们还怎么去月球啊?
How're we gonna get to the moon?
噢 还记得吗? 这是在歪脖子树旁那次
Oh. It's that time in the Twisty Tree, remember?
冰球队突然出现 爸爸妈妈在旁边加油
The hockey team showed up and Mom and Dad were there cheering.
看看她 多开心
Look at her. Having fun and laughing.
- 我喜欢这个  - 我也喜欢
- I love this one. - I love that one too.
- 好姑娘 现在你也懂了吗  - 是的
- Attagirl. Now you're getting it.  - Yeah.
那天土拨鼠队输了那场大型季后赛
It was the day the Prairie dogs lost the big playoff game.
莱莉没有打入决胜球 她感觉很难受 她想退队
Riley missed the winning shot. She felt awful, she wanted to quit.
对不起 我又开始忧愁了
Sorry. I went sad again, didn't I?
我告诉你 我们回去后再想办法解决 好吗?
I'll tell you what. We can keep working on that when we get back, okay?
好
Okay.
我只是没搞明白
I just don't understand.
为什么我们的搬运车会跑去了德克萨斯?
Why did our moving van even go to Texas?
顾客太多搞混了
Multiple customers.
可是 你们向我们承诺过会在5号送到
Well, we were promised delivery on the 5th.
啊哈
Uh-huh.
不好意思 你真的没有办法再催一下吗?
Excuse me. Isn't there any way you think you can rush it?
诚实岛怎么了?
Honesty Island?
喔喔 小心!
Woo. Look out!
啊啊啊!
Awww!
快走!
Come on!
坚持住!
Hold on!
- 快点  - 过来
- Hurry up.  - Join over here.
- 快... 快... 快  - 我抓住了
- Go... go... go.  - I got it.
- 拉  - 拉
- Pull.  - Pull.
那是我们回家的路
That was our way home.
我们又丢了一个岛 这是怎么了?
We lost another island. What is happening?
你没听说吗? 莱莉要离家出走
Haven't you heard? Riley is running away.
什么?
What?
等等 等一下 伙计们
Wait wait. Hang on, guys.
我们真要这么做吗? 我的意思是 这是个很严肃的事情
Are we really doing this? I mean, this is serious.
听着 我们没有核心记忆了
Look. We have no core memories.
你想要莱莉开心吗?
You want Riley to be happy?
那我们就得回到明尼苏达去制造更多的核心记忆
Let's get back to Minnesota and make more.
乐乐 如果我们快一点 我们还能阻止她
Joy. If we hurry, we can still stop her.
亲情岛 走
Family Island. Let's go.
乐乐
Joy.
乐乐 太危险了 我们来不及的
Joy. It's too dangerous. We won't make it in time.
但是 那是我们回去的唯一的路啊
But, that's our only way back.
回忆管
A recall tube.
我们可以通过它回去
We can get recall.
玩得开心点 亲爱的
Have a great day, sweetheart.
- 放学见 小猴子  - 我们爱你
- See you after school, monkey.  - We love you.
快走 跑 跑! 快走!
Go, run run! Go!
哇哦 哇哦 忧忧
Whoa whoa, Sadness.
忧忧 停下
Sadness. Stop.
- 你伤害到莱莉了  - 不 不 不 我又犯错了
- You're hurting Riley.  - No, no, no. I did it again.
如果你进去了 这些核心记忆也会变得伤心的
If you get in here, these core memories will get sad.
对不起
I'm sorry.
- 莱莉需要开心  - 乐乐?
- Riley needs to be happy.  - Joy?
啊啊啊!
Aahhh!
乐乐 啊啊!
Joy. Ahh!
乐乐!
Joy!
乐乐?
Joy?
乐乐!
Joy!
乐乐 乐乐 你在干什么? 停下来 好不好?
Joy. Joy, what're you doing? Will you stop it, please?
你还不明白吗? 我们被困在这里 出不去了
Don't you get it, Joy? We're stuck down here.
我们被遗忘了
We're forgotten.
你还记得
Do you remember,
她过去画画的时候伸出舌头的样子吗?
how she used to stick her tongue out when she was coloring?
我可以听她讲一整天的故事
I could listen to her stories all day.
我只是想让莱莉开心而已
I just wanted Riley to be happy.
那天土拨鼠队输了那场大型季后赛
It was the day the Prairie dogs lost the big playoff game.
莱莉没有打入决胜球 她感觉很难受
Riley missed the winning shot. She felt awful.
她想退队
She wanted to quit.
忧忧
Sadness.
爸爸妈妈 队里的小伙伴们
Mom and Dad. The team.
他们来安慰莱莉是因为她伤心了
They came to help because of sadness.
我们必须要回到上面去
We have to get back up there.
乐乐 我们被困在这下面了
Joy, we're stuck down here.
跟在另一个星球上没啥两样
We might as well be on another planet.
另一个星球
Another planet.
# 你最爱玩的伙伴是谁? #
# Who's your friend who likes to play? #
# 他的火箭让你欢呼"万岁!" #
# His rocket makes you yell "Hooray!" #
# 谁不但十全十美 还要把这唱出来? #
# Who's the best in every way, and wants to sing this song to say? #
# 你最爱玩的伙伴是谁? 冰棒 冰棒 #
# Who's your friend who likes to play? Bing Bong. Bing Bong. #
# 他的火箭让你欢呼"万岁"! #
# His rocket makes you yell "Hooray!" #
快进来
Hop in.
# 你最爱玩的伙伴是谁? 冰棒 冰棒 #
# Who's your friend who likes to play? Bing Bong. Bing Bong. #
# 他的火箭让你欢呼"万岁"! 冰棒 冰棒 #
# His rocket makes you yell "Hooray!" Bing Bong, Bing Bong #
# 谁不但十全十美 还要把这唱出来? #
# Who's the best in every way, and wants to sing this song to say? #
# 他的火箭让你欢呼"耶" ! 冰棒 冰棒 #
# His rocket makes you yell "Hooray!" Bing Bong, Bing Bong #
# 谁不但十全十美 还要把这唱出来... #
# Who's the best in every way, and wants to sing this song to say... #
啊啊啊！
Ahhh!
再来!
Come on!
哇!
Whoa!
哦!
Oh.
乐乐 快点 我们再来一次
Come on Joy, one more time.
我有预感这次我们能行
I got a feeling about this one.
# 他的火箭让你欢呼"万岁!" 冰棒 冰棒 #
# His rocket makes you yell "Hooray!" Bing Bong, Bing Bong #
# 谁不但十全十美 还要把这唱出来 #
# Who's the best in every way, and wants to sing this song to say. #
# 你最爱玩的伙伴是谁? 冰棒 冰棒 #
# Who's your friend who likes to play? Bing Bong. Bing Bong. #
大声点! 大声点! 乐乐 唱大声点!
Louder! Louder! Joy, sing louder!
我们就要成功了
We're gonna make it.
呜呼
Woo-hoo.
冰棒 我们成功了!
Bing Bong, we did it!
我们... 冰棒?
We... Bing Bong?
冰棒!
Bing Bong!
呀 哈 哈! 你成功了! 哈 哈!
Yah ha ha! You made it! Ha ha!
快去! 去救莱莉 哈哈哈
Go! Go save Riley. Ha ha ha.
替我带她去月球 好吗?
Take her to the moon for me. Okay?
噢
Oh.
我会带她去的 冰棒
I'll try. Bing Bong.
我保证
I promise.
我们回来了!
We're home!
莱莉? 莱莉?
Riley? Riley?
我来打她的手机
I'll call her cell.
噢 太糟糕了
Oh, this is terrible.
等等 有人在朝我们走过来?
Wait. Is that someone walking towards us?
我们... 到街那边去
Let... Let's cross the street.
妈妈
是妈妈 被她发现了
It's Mom. She's on to us.
- 怎么办?  - 我的袋子在哪?
- What do we do?  - Where's my bag?
莱莉需要核心记忆
Riley needs to get core memories.
我们继续走
We keep going.
忧忧!
Sadness!
忧忧? 忧忧?
Sadness? Sadness?
拜托 忧忧 你在哪?
Come on, Sadness. Where are you?
好 如果我是忧忧 我会在哪呢?
Okay. If I were Sadness, where would I be?
噢 一切都糟透了 我的腿也不能动了
Oh. Everything is awful and my legs don't work.
你必须拖着我走 然后我摸着...
And you have to drag me around while I touch all the...
哦 不 又是妈妈 怎么办?
Oh no. It's Mom again. What do we do?
噢
Uh.
我们真是疯了 她不应该离家出走
This is madness. She shouldn't run away.
我们让她放弃这个想法
Let's get this idea out of her head.
忧忧?
Sadness?
- 忧忧  - 乐乐?
- Sadness.  - Joy?
等等 忧忧
Wait. Sadness.
让我走吧 莱莉没有我会活得更好
Just let me go. Riley is better off without me.
回来!
Come back!
明白了 你的丈夫被一头大象吹走了
Okay. You're saying your husband was blown away by an elephant.
- 有其他人和他一起吗?  - 有 就是她!
- Was he with anyone?  - Yes. And there she is!
嘿! 回来!
Hey! Come back here!
算了吧 杰克 这里是白云镇
Forget it, Jake. It's Cloud Town.
忧忧
Sadness.
- 我只会让所有的事情更糟糕  - 等等我
- I only make everything worse.  - Wait.
忧忧 我们必须把你带回...
Sadness, we got to get you back to...
- 它被卡住了  - 哦 真好
- It's stuck.  - Oh, great.
- 你说什么? 什么叫"它被卡住了"?  - 现在怎么办?
- What? What do you mean it's stuck?  - Now what?
不 不 不 怎么回事?
No, no, no. What is this?
- 怎么把它停下来?  - 有了
- How do we stop it?  - I got it.
让她感觉害怕 她肯定会改主意的
Make her feel scared. That will make her change her mind.
- 好主意  - 我知道是个好主意 快动手
- Brilliant.  - I know it's brilliant. Do it.
设备全都失灵了 为什么它不工作了?
Nothing's working. Why isn't it working?
- 让我试试  - 等等 你把它搞坏了
- Let me try.  - Wait. You broke it.
- 快点 快点  - 让我来 走开
- Move. Move.  - Let me do it. Get out of here.
不行
No.
伙计们 莱莉已经没有任何感受了
Guys. We can't make Riley feel anything.
我们做了什么?
What have we done?
嘿 嘿 看这边 你之前说的话还算不算数?
Hey. Hey, look at me. Did you mean what you said before?
我愿意为莱莉去死 我愿意为莱莉去死
I would die for Riley. I would die for Riley.
好 好 好了 不要说了 证明给我看
Yeah yeah. Okay, haircut. Time to prove it.
我愿意为莱莉去死 我愿意为莱莉去死
I would die for Riley. I would die for Riley.
我愿意莱莉去死 我愿意为莱莉去死
够了 我不干了
That's it. I fold.
喔...
Whao...
- 喔喔  - 喔喔
- Whoa.  - Whoa.
喔  喔  放松 稳住了
Whoa. Whoa. Easy. Okay.
- 呜... 呜.... 呜  - 喔
- Woo... woo... woo.  - Whoa.
我真是疯了 我真是疯了
This is crazy. This is crazy.
不 不 不 乐乐 你要肯定自己
No no no. Joy, be positive.
我肯定是疯了
I'm positive this is crazy.
现在!
NOW!
为了莱莉... 为了莱莉...
For Riley... For Riley...
- 乐乐?  - 抓住了
- Joy? - Hang on.
噢 我真希望乐乐能在这里
Oh, I wished Joy was here.
是乐乐
It's Joy.
让开 呀!
Stand back. Yah!
干得好
That worked.
好 你聪明 你想办法啊?
Well, what would you do if you're so smart?
我会告诉你 但是你这么笨根本不会明白
I'll tell you. But you're too dumb to understand.
- 你说什么!  - 你的小脑袋肯定是一团糟
- What!  - Of course your tiny brain is confused.
估计我只好用你的智商能理解的水平告诉你了
Guess I'll just have to dumb it down to your level.
不好意思 我没办法像你那么傻 但是我可以试一试
Sorry, I don't speak moron as well as you. But let me try.
嘟
Duh.
啊啊啊啊啊!
AAAHHHHHH!
哦 感谢上帝 你回来了
Oh. Thank goodness you're back.
- 现在情况一团糟  - 我们... 我们... 我们想到了这个主意
- Things are really messed up.  - We... we... we found this idea.
噢 不
Oh no.
乐乐 靠你了 过去吧
Joy, you got to fix this. Get up there.
- 忧忧 这必须要靠你  - 我?
- Sadness, it's up to you.  - Me?
- 忧忧?  - 忧忧?
- Sadness?  - Sadness?
- 忧忧?
- Sadness?
- 我不行 乐乐  - 不 你行的
- I can't, Joy.  - Yes, you can.
莱莉需要你
Riley needs you.
好吧
Okay.
等等 停车 我要下车
Wait. Stop. I want to get off.
好 谢谢 我们会的
Alright. Thank you, we will.
- 莱莉的老师一整天都没有见到她  - 什么?
- Her teacher hasn't even seen Riley all day.  - What?
- 她今天走的时候穿的是什么?  - 我简直不能相信这一切
- What was she wearing last?  -  I can't believe this.
你能记得...
Do you even remember what...
- 莱莉  - 嘿 你在这儿
- Riley.  - Hey. There you are.
- 谢谢上帝  - 噢 我们担心死了
- Thank goodness.  - Oh, we were worried sick.
- 你去哪了? 这么晚了  - 噢
- Where have you been? It's so late.  - Oh.
莱莉 发生了什么事? 你还好吗?
Riley, what happened? Are you alright?
我知道你们不想让我... 但是...
I know you don't want me to... But...
我想家了
I missed home.
我想明尼苏达了
I missed Minnesota.
你们希望我开心
You need me to be happy.
但是...
But...
我想我的老朋友和我的冰球队
I want my old friends and my hockey team.
我想回家
I want to go home.
不要生我的气
Please don't be mad.
- 哦 亲爱的  - 我们没有生气
- Oh, sweetie.  - We're not mad.
你知道吗? 我也想明尼苏达了
You know what? I missed Minnesota too.
我想念那片我们常去游玩的树林
I missed the woods that we took hikes.
还有你过去玩耍的院子
And the backyard where you used to play.
春湖 你在那里学会的滑冰
Spring lake. Where you learned to skate.
过来
Come here.
嘿 我喜欢这个新样子
Hey. I'm liking this new view.
友情岛变大了
Friendship Island has expanded.
真高兴他们终于开放了和气争吵区
Glad they finally opened that friendly argument section.
我喜欢吸血鬼爱情悲剧岛
I like Tragic Vampire Romance Island.
时尚岛 大家都安静
Fashion Island. Everyone shut up.
男孩乐队岛? 希望只是暂时的
Boy Band Island? Hope that's just a phase.
爱说什么说什么 我觉得这一切都很好
Say what you want. I think it's all beautiful.
好了 你们可以用了
Alright. Here you go.
你们升级的工作台已经可以运行了
Your new expanded console is up and running.
- 哇喔  - 哇
- Whoa.  - Wow.
- 酷 升级了  - 呜
- Cool. Upgrade.  -  Woo.
是 呼呼 哎呦 等等 刚才是我吗?
Aye, ho ho. Whoops, wait, did I just do that?
嗨 伙计们 "青春期"是什么意思?
Hey. Guys, what's "PUBERTY"?
不知道 应该不是什么重要的东西
I don't know. It's probably not important.
哇喔 我现在拥有全套脏话的使用权了
Whoa. I have access to the entire curse word library.
这个新的控制台真是...
This new console is the ...
不好意思 又是我 我的错
Sorry. I did it again. My bad.
他们要去冰球场了
They're getting to the rink.
听着 上场之后 要全力进攻
Now, when you get out there, you be aggressive.
- 我知道 爸爸  - 但是也不能太拼
- I know, Dad.  - But not too aggressive.
你们知道 你们不用每场比赛都来的
You know. You guys don't have to come to every game.
你在开玩笑吗? 我不会错过任何一场的!
Are you kidding? I'm not missing one!
- 冲 雾笛队!  - 冲 莱莉!
- Go Fog Horns!  - Go Riley!
- 雾... 笛...  - 好好
- Fog.. Horns...  - Okay okay.
- 我要走了  - 最棒的...!
- I got to go.  - the best...!
- 噢  - 他们爱我们
- Oh.  - They love us.
对 爸爸妈妈真酷
Yeah. Mom and Dad are pretty cool.
伙计们 他们确实很酷 但是我们不能表现出来
Guys, of course they are. But we can't show it.
耶! 耶!
Yeh. Yeh.
她喜欢我们化的这个妆
She loved the face painting.
哈 我告诉过你这是个很好的主意
Ha. Told you it was a great idea.
- 近来他最好的主意  - 他真是一个好男人
- Best idea he's had in a while.  - He's a really good guy.
- 啊  - 噢
- Ah.  - Oh.
以防万一而已
Just in case.
噢
Oh.
对不起
Sorry.
- 啊啊啊!  - 发现女孩! 发现女孩!
- Aww!  - GIRL! GIRL!
- 噢 噢  - 发现女孩!
- Oh oh.  - GIRL!
唔 好 再见
Uh. Okay. Bye.
嘿 莱莉
Hey Riley.
你行的
You got this.
- 准备好了吗?  - 嗯
- You ready?  - Yeah.
好 现在我们来玩一把冰球
Alright. Let's play some hockey.
- 好 怒怒 你来控制  - 抢到冰球 不然你就死定了!
- Alright, Anger. Take over.  - Give us that puck or you're dead meat!
左边 左边!
On her left. On her left!
这次不要弄得全身臭汗就好了
Let's just try not to get all smelly this time.
哦 爸爸妈妈看着我们失败
Oh. Mom and Dad are watching us fail.
不会的!
Not for long!
没错 最近这段时间我们挫折不断
We've been through a lot lately, that's for sure.
但是我们仍然爱着我们的女孩
But we sill love our girl.
她有特别要好的新朋友 还有很棒的新房子
She has great new friends and great new house.
一切都好的不能再好了
Things couldn't be better.
毕竟 莱莉现在已经12岁了
After all, Riley is 12 now.
还会有什么问题呢?
What could happen?
后有彩蛋 不要走开
-=圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hdscg.com/=-
仅供翻译交流使用, 禁止用于商业用途
协调: 影子   校对: 颐译辜形
翻译: 灵峰 肉肉君 jackhawktaobao 喵喵 沉默的土豆
那谁能告诉我旧金山是哪一年建立的?
And who can tell me what year San Francisco was founded?
有人知道吗?
Anyone?
- 乔丹  - 唔
- Jordan.  - Uh.
还要这样下去多久?
How much more of this?
离暑假还有五个月两个星期零四天
5 months 2 weeks and 4 days until summer vacation.
然后就是和帅哥去巴哈马
Then it's off to the Bahamas with you know who.
来啊 和我一起飞 宝贝
Come. Fly with me, criancinha.
- 啊  - 啊
- Ah.  - Ah.
过的开心一点
Have a nice day.
我们到底是气什么?
What are we mad about?
不知道 和托伊气的是一件事吧
I don't know. Whatever Troy is mad about.
托伊又气什么?
What's Troy mad about?
- 不知道  - 不知道
- I don't know.  - I don't know.
我知道 全都知道
I know, totally.
我们是彻头彻尾的骗子 你觉得他们可以看穿我们吗?
We are a total fraud. Do you think they can see through us?
当然不可能 我们带着眼影呢
Of course not. We're wearing eye shadow.
装酷真累
Being cool is so exhausting.
谁是小寿星? 哈
Who's the birthday girl? Huh.
嗨 你们好?
Hey. Hello?
戏剧学校待了六年混成这样
6 years of drama school for this.
- 什么?  - 快开啊
- What?  - Let's move.
大家听着 没什么 这样很好
Look. This is okay. This is fine.
我们只需要去我们的快乐地
We just need to go to our happy place.
- 啊!  - 啊啊啊!
- Ah!  - AHHH!
我闻到了食物的味道
那个人在吃东西
抢过来